We're on the home stretch.
거의 다 됐어요
This is the final step in the environment setup, and it's an easy one.
환경 설정의 마지막 단계입니다 쉬운 거죠
It's one that's easy to make mistakes as well.
실수하기 쉬운 분야이기도 하죠
But I'm going to guide you through it and there'll be no problems whatsoever.
하지만 제가 안내할 거고 아무 문제 없을 거예요
I'm going to show it to you both on a mac and a PC all in one video, so you guys can see how it works
맥과 PC를 한 비디오에 보여드릴게요 둘 다 어떻게 작동하는지 보실
for both.
수 있게요
And it's pretty simple.
아주 간단해요
It's called creating a dot env file, which is a common way to store secrets in a way that you can access
.Infile 생성이라고 하죠 기밀을 저장하는 일반적인 방법이에요 프로젝트 안에서 액세스할 수 있는
in your project that don't get checked into source code control doesn't go into into git, which means
방법이죠 소스 코드 컨트롤에 체크되지 않고 Git으로 들어가지 않는 기밀이요 여러분의 기밀은
that your secrets are safe.
안전하다는 뜻이죠
We're going to start with a mac.
맥으로 시작할 거예요
Here I am, I am going to go into my projects folder that we set up into LM engineering.
제 프로젝트 폴더로 가겠습니다 LM 엔지니어링으로 설정해둔 거죠
So we are now in the project root directory, as I say.
이제 프로젝트 루트 디렉터리에 들어왔어요
Um, and what I'm going to do is create a file called dot env.
.Infi라는 파일을 만들 거예요
And the way that you create a file from, from the, the way you bring up an editor in here is you can
파일을 생성하는 방법은 여기서 에디터를 가져오는 방법은 아주 인기 있는
use nano, which is a very popular tool.
도구인 나노를 사용하는 거죠
And the name of our file, the thing we're going to create is going to be called dot EMV, literally
파일 이름, 우리가 만들 것은 .MV라고 하겠습니다 말 그대로 마침표죠
And then the letters EMV.
EMV라는 글자도 있어요
Now here's the thing.
문제는 이거예요
This is a fussy step.
까다로운 단계예요
The name of the file must be exactly dot EMV.
파일 이름은 정확히 .MV여야 해요
It can't be like my keys dot EMV or EMV and it can't be dot EMV, dot text or anything like that.
. EMV나 EMV 같은 키도 안 되고 . EMV나 .Text 같은 것도 안 돼요
It's got to be exactly dot EMV, otherwise it doesn't find it.
정확히 .MV가 아니면 찾을 수 없어요
So that's that's the rule.
그게 규칙이에요
And now that I've done that, up comes a new empty file called dot EMV.
이제 다 됐으니 .MV라는 새 빈 파일이 뜨네요
And what I'm going to put in here is very simple.
여기에 Put은 건 아주 간단해요
And of course this is all laid out in the in the readme.
물론 이 모든 건 대본 읽기에 나와 있죠
But I'm going to put in this file just open AI underscore API underscore key equals.
이 파일에 그냥 인공지능 밑줄 API =을 열게요
And now I put in here the key itself that that I have hopefully stored very safely from the last video.
이제 키를 넣을게요. 지난 비디오에서 아주 안전하게 저장해둔 거죠.
And it begins scmproj dash blah blah blah.
스크프록 대시 어쩌고저쩌고로 시작해요
Put that in the file and don't have any.
파일에 넣고, 없어요. Put it up Put it it up Put it up Put it up Put it up Put it up Put it up Put it it up Put it it up Put it
Don't have a space before the equals sign or after the equals sign.
= 기호 앞이나 뒤에 빈칸이 있으면 안 돼요
And there's one other like really unpleasant.
정말 불쾌한 게 하나 더 있어요
Gotcha.
알았어요
If you've if you use the notebook on the notes application on Mac, I use that a lot.
Mac의 노트 응용 프로그램에 있는 노트를 사용하면, 전 많이 써요
Sometimes if you paste something in there and then press enter and copy it out, it replaces hyphens
가끔 뭔가를 붙여넣기 한 후 엔터를 누르고 복사하면 하이픈을 긴 대시로 대체해요
with long dashes if you're not careful.
조심하지 않으면요
So just make sure that that whatever.
그러니 확실히 하세요
If you haven't copied it straight from that website, that nothing has got mangled in your key.
웹사이트에서 복사한 게 아니라면 열쇠는 멀쩡할 거예요
That was a really hard problem.
정말 어려운 문제였어요
That it took me a while to track down that one student had, but maybe it's just a rare situation that
그 학생을 찾는 데 시간이 좀 걸렸다는 거요 하지만 그런 일은 아주 드물죠
But anyways, if you've been careful, we've got the key just like this.
어쨌든 조심하면 이런 열쇠를 얻을 수 있어요
You've got the full key laid out there, and then you press, as it says on the on the bottom of the
전체 키가 있고, 버튼을 누르면 화면 하단에 나와 있듯이
screen on a mac, command O or control O to save, and X gets out of it.
Mac에 저장 명령 O나 컨트롤 O가 있고 X가 나오죠
Now there's one thing to look out for.
이제 조심해야 할 게 하나 남았어요
If I do an LHS, you'll see that there isn't a EMV file here, and you'll also not see one when we look
LHS를 하면 여기 EMV 파일이 없는 게 보이시죠 JupyterLab에도
in JupyterLab.
없어요
And the reason is because any file that begins with a dot.
그 이유는 점으로 시작하는 파일은 다 그렇기 때문이죠
A mac considers to be a hidden file, a secret file, and if you want to see that, you'd have to do
Mac은 숨겨진 파일로 간주합니다 비밀 파일이요 그걸 보고 싶다면 ls-a를
ls minus A, and then you see all of the hidden files, and you'll now see included.
하세요 그럼 숨겨진 파일들이 보이죠 이제 포함된 걸 보실 수 있어요
On the bottom left there is EMV.
왼쪽 아래가 EMV예요
And if I want to see what contents that has.
어떤 콘텐츠가 있는지 보고 싶을 때도요
You'll see that it has the OpenAI API key.
OpenAI API 키가 있는 게 보이시죠
And of course in your case hopefully you have a full key in there.
물론 당신 경우엔 전체 키가 있길 바라요
So that's it.
그게 다예요
That's the Mac version.
맥 버전이에요
Let's look on a PC.
PC에서 찾아보죠
Let me flip over to my emulator of PCs over here.
여기 PC 에뮬레이터로 넘어가죠
Here we have it.
여기 있네요
So on a PC the thing to use is the program called notepad.
PC에서는 메모장이라는 프로그램을 사용해요
And you can press the windows and R to run and then type notepad and press okay.
실행하려면 윈도우와 R을 누르고 메모장을 입력하고 확인을 누르세요
And up comes notepad.
메모장이 나왔어요
Uh, in this notepad we say open AI underscore API underscore key equals.
이 메모장에는 열린 인공지능 밑줄 API 키 =이라고 적어요
And then you paste in your key which should start scmproj dash blah blah blah blah blah.
그런 다음 scmproj 대시 어쩌고저쩌고 키를 붙여넣어요
That should go in here.
여기에 넣어야 해요
And then you go file and you go save as.
그런 다음 파일로 가서 as로 저장해요
Now you then will have to navigate around to find your way to the LM engineering folder, which I've
이제 LM 엔지니어링 폴더로 가는 길을 찾아야 합니다 제가 이미
already got set up right here.
여기 설정해뒀죠
And now.
지금요
There's like a little gotcha here, a little trick.
여기 속임수가 있어요
You have to know where it says save as type.
어디에 타입으로 저장하라고 돼 있는지 알아야 해요
You have to change that to be all files.
모든 파일로 바꿔야 해요
And now in here you can type dot EMV.
이제 여기서 .MV를 입력할 수 있어요
And I will save this right now.
지금 당장 저장할게요
And that should be done.
그래야만 해요
Exit.
출구예요
And now back over here.
다시 이쪽으로요
If I do an LZ we do see that there is a dot EMV and it doesn't have any nasty name to it.
LZ를 하면 .MV가 보이는데 이상한 이름은 없어요
So that has been created successfully and that is the final step.
성공적으로 만들어졌고 이게 마지막 단계예요
We are now finally ready to actually go and do a lab.
드디어 실험할 준비가 됐어요
Congratulations!
축하해요
I guess I should hold the congratulations until you see it working in the lab, but tentative.
축하 인사는 실험실에서 효과를 보기 전까진 미뤄야겠네요
Congratulations on getting it this far and I can't wait to see you for the next video.
여기까지 온 걸 축하해요 다음 영상에서 빨리 보고 싶네요
When we're actually going to do something.
실제로 뭔가를 할 때요
See you there.
거기서 봐요